Mother.
妈妈
Don't come over, Ran.
不要过来 兰
It was a dream.
是梦
What... You dreamed that I got shot?
什么……梦见我被枪射中
That's why you called me early in the morning?
所以一大早打电话过来
I'm worried about you.
因为我很担心
Lawyers have lots of enemies too.
律师有时候也会有仇家的
You think too much, Ran.
你想太多了 兰
You only had that dream because
因为你看过太多事件
you've seen too many criminal cases.
所以才会做这种梦
Anyway I'm just glad that you are fine.
但是你没事我就放心了
By the way, you looked much younger
对了 在梦里出现的妈妈
in my dream.
比现在还要年轻一些哦
What are you talking about? I am still young.
说什么！我现在还是很年轻
Is that so? Sorry if that didn't sound right.
是吗 我说错话了 对不起啦
Good to hear that.
你明白就好
See you at 7 p.m. tonight. Dad and Conan are looking forward to seeing you.
今晚七点 爸爸和柯南也期待着
That kid... She still remembers that?
那个孩子……还记得吗？
Conan.
柯南
What's wrong? Why did you get up so early?
怎么啦 这么早
No, nothing.
不 没事
Sorry to have woken you up.
对不起 吵醒你
That's right. Tonight we'll have dinner with Ran's mother.
原来是今天晚上 和小兰的妈妈吃饭
That woman is so hard to deal with.
那个伯母 最难应付了
(Detective Conan The Fourteenth Target)
名侦探柯南 14番的目的
I am Shinichi Kudo, a high school student and also a detective.
我是高中生侦探 工藤新一
When I was at an amusement park
当我跟青梅竹马的同学毛利兰
with Ran Mouri my childhood sweetheart
一起到游乐园玩时
I witnessed a transaction between criminal syndicates.
却目击了黑暗组织的交易现场
At that time I paying attention only to what's happening,
当时我只顾着偷看交易
ignored that one of them had come up behind me.
却忽略了从背后来的另一个同伙
I was forced to take a drug.
我被那个人强灌了毒药
When I woke up,
当我醒来的时候
my body had shrunk.
身体竟然缩小了
If they know that Shinichi Kudo is still alive,
如果被他们知道工藤新一还活着
they'll try to kill me and even my relatives and friends.
肯定又会招来杀身之祸,还会连累周遭的亲人
So I listened to Hiroshi Agasa's advice and hid my true identity.
听从阿笠博士的建议 隐藏了身份
When Ran asked about my name
在被兰追问名字的时候
the name Conan Edogawa suddenly hit me.
情急之下讲出叫江户川柯南
In order to get more information about the people in that organization,
为了搜集那些人的情报
I decided to stay with Ran whose father is a detective.
住进了父亲开着侦探所的兰的家
That's right he is Ran's father.
对 他就是兰的父亲
Now he is a very famous detective.
现在是非常有名的名侦探
His name is Kogoro Mouri.
毛利小五郎
Actually he's not a good detective.
其实他是个没用的侦探
I guess everyone would know
解决问题的人是谁
who actually solved all the cases.
大家应该都知道了吧
My secret is related to two of Hiroshi Agasa's inventions.
那个秘密关系着阿笠博士的两个发明
The first one is this,
第一个 就是这个
the stun-gun wrist-watch.
手表型的麻醉枪
After using the crosshairs on the lid to aim,
将表面的瞄准器对准
I'll push a button and shoot an anesthetic needle
按下按钮 就会射出麻醉针
which puts a person into sleep instantly.
能够让人一瞬间睡着
The second one is this voice-changing bow-tie.
然后第二个 蝴蝶结变声器
By turning the knob on the back,
只要转动后面的转轮
I can mimic the voices of
从老人到小孩的声音
elders and children.
全部都能够模仿
And these power-assisted shoes
必杀的绝招
are the best items I have.
就是这个增强力量球鞋
By using electric current and magnetic force to stimulate the acupuncture points on my feet,
利用电流和磁力刺激脚的穴道
they push my muscles to their fullest potential.
把肌肉发挥到最大功能
If I need to chase after a criminal,
如果是要追踪犯人的话
I'll use this turbo engine skateboard.
就用这个装有双引擎的滑板
Lastly there's also this life-saving tool,
最后 还有一个特别的救命工具
the elastic suspenders.
就是这个伸缩背带
It stretches or shortens with a push of a button.
按按钮 就能变长变短
This is an excellent tool.
是个超级棒的工具
I haven't caught them yet
虽然我还没抓到他们
but criminal cases won't wait for me.
但是事件不会停下来等我
Though my body has shrunk my mind is still the same.
身体虽然缩小了 头脑还是那么棒
I leave no crime unsolved.
没有休假的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相只有一个
Hey, Genta... are you gonna keep eating?
啊 元太……你还要吃吗
It's none of your business.
你管我吃多少
This is black chocolate flavored ice lolly.
这次是黑巧克力冰棒
I heard the adults all love this flavor.
是属于大人的味道
Really?
真的吗？
How's that even possible?
怎么可能
Anyway he's so slow.
但是真慢啊
Check this out!
快看 快看
It says that Conan and I are meant for each other!
我和柯南的命相非常合
Is that machine... out of order?
该不会是故障了吧……那台机器
Genta, you should say that
应该这么说 元太
fortune-telling with poker cards is a hoax.
那种扑克牌算命都是乱讲的
I'll do Conan's next.
我也来试试柯南的
His birthday is...
他的生日是……
Hey don't ask about other people's fortune.
喂喂 别乱替别人算命
This must be about me and Conan!
一定是在讲我和柯南
A's prediction.
A的预感
A~ What year is that game from?
A~ 那是几年前的游戏啊
Hey! What does A refer to?
喂！A是什么意思？
A means...
A的意思就是说……
Something before B.
就是指在B的前面
I think it must refer to fried shrimps!
我想是指炸虾的意思
So it doesn't mean kissing...
原来不是Kiss的意思啊……
Sorry I'm late.
对不起 我来晚了
Come on we've been waiting for so long!
真是的 等你好久啊博士
Sorry.
对不起
Awesome!
好壮观！
There are so many kinds of airplanes!
好多种飞机啊！
They say there's a helicopter flight simulator here.
这里好像可以操纵模拟直升机
Sounds fun.
好像很有趣的样子
What a pity.
非常可惜
Why is that, Conan?
为什么？柯南
It says here that only the students above the fifth grade
上面写着 操纵模拟直升机
could try the helicopter simulator.
必须要小学五年级以上才行
What a bummer!
真无趣
Sorry guys. When I was in the fifth grade,
真是对不起 我在五年级的时候
I already had enough of this game.
已经玩得不想再玩了
Ah, then let me tell you an interesting story instead.
啊 那么就让我来讲些有趣的事吧
Hey! If we don't stop him now,
喂！如果不及时阻止的话
he'll tell us a long story again.
就会有听不完的故事了
Leave it to me.
包在我身上
What's on the photos we just saw...
在刚才那些照片上所出现的……
It's time for a quiz!
现在是Quiz时间
What's this all of a sudden?
为什么突然窜出来
Three children who were born on
在元旦和愚人节和小孩之日
New Year's Day April Fool's Day and Children's day
所出生的三个孩子
formed a club.
一起组织个会
The question is... what was their club called?
问题……会是什么会呢？
The hint is that it's an animal which could fly in the sky
提示是和飞机一样
like an airplane.
在天空飞行的动物
A flying animal?
在天上飞的动物
Conan, have you figured it out?
柯南已经知道答案了吗？
Of course! Just add their birthdays together.
当然 把三人的生日合在一起就是答案
Birthday?
生日？
January 1st April 1st May 5th together.
一月一日 四月一日 五月五日
October 7th?
十月七日
That's right. October 7th.
对 就是十月七日
That's reindeer.
就是驯鹿
"To-na-kai". (Sounds like reindeer in Japanese)
10 7 会(驯鹿)
Reindeer would pull Santa's sleigh
在圣诞节拉着圣诞老人
in the sky on Christmas.
在天上飞着
Oh...
噢……
Correct!
正确！
Just as I expected Conan!
不愧是柯南
Isn't that Eimei Shishido?
那个人不是宍户永明吗？
He's so cool!
真帅
Thanks for coming.
谢谢光临
Next person please.
有请下一位
All right. Here you are.
好了 请拿好
Thank you so much. I'm a big fan of yours, Mr. Nishina.
谢谢 我是仁科先生的书迷
I hope that you could write more delicious books in the future.
今后也希望能够多写些好味的书
"Delicious" is such a nice word to describe the books.
好味的书真是个好形容词
Thank you.
谢谢你
He's even more handsome than his photo.
他比照片上还要棒
He's my type of guy.
我最喜欢那种类型的
Oh you're so shameless...
不怕羞
What a reckless driver.
真是个粗鲁的驾驶员
That's...
那个人是……
It really is the model, Nana Osanai!
真是模特小山内奈奈
I'm not interested in that kind of person.
我对那种人没兴趣
Let's have some tea.
快点去喝茶吧
When are you going to have dinner with your mother?
几点？和你母亲的饭局
Seven o'clock.
七点
You did all the planning again, right?
这次也是兰计划好的吧
Yes.
嗯
You sure put in a lot of effort.
你也真是辛苦
It has been ten years since your mom left home right?
是十年前吧 你妈妈离家出走
Yes, she left when I was seven.
对 在我七岁的时候
I remember they had a big fight.
我还记得他们吵得很凶
They separated because they seemed to be incompatible personality wise.
分居的理由好像是性格不合
However not long after that,
然后过了不久
your mom started to make a name for herself as a lawyer.
小兰的妈妈在律师界开始出名
Contrary to her,
然后相反的
your dad quit his job as a police officer
你爸爸辞去警察的工作
and started a detective agency which has no clients.
开了间没生意的侦探社
What did you say?
你讲什么……！
Oh right! Your dad
对了 你爸爸最近
has suddenly become a famous detective.
突然变成名侦探
Honestly if you were not with him,
要是没有小兰在身边的话
he would have become a ruined man long ago.
我想他早就不知道堕落到哪里去了
I don't think it would've become like that...
没那么离谱啦……
But it's true that my mom could take good care of herself.
但是相反的妈妈就很会照顾自己
I'm back...
我回来了……
You are back.
你回来了啊
Ah! Uncle, you are still not ready?
啊！叔叔还没准备好吗？
He went out at noon to play mahjong
从中午就跑出去打麻将
and just came back.
刚刚才回来
Come on, why do we have to eat with Eri?
真是的 为何一定要和英理吃饭
Stop whining and hurry up.
别发牢骚了 快点收拾
Now we are with Katsuyoshi Asahi, the owner of the plaza
现在看到的是今天在东京湾附近新开幕的
which has just opened near the Tokyo Bay today.
娱乐广场的老板旭胜义先生
We came to his home to ask him some questions.
到他家进行访问 问一些问题
Conan.
柯南
I'll go get changed!
我也去换衣服
Sorry we're late, mom.
妈妈对不起 我们迟到了
It's all right. Someone must have
没关系 一定是某人
played mahjong until very late.
又去玩麻将玩到很晚吧
She's still so sharp.
她还是那么厉害
I'll have to watch what I say in front of her.
在伯母面前绝对不能讲错话
Good evening, Conan.
晚上好 柯南
Good... evening.
晚……上好
Long time no see, Mr. Mouri.
好久不见 毛利先生
Hey, Mr. Tsuji.
这不是辻先生嘛
Who's that?
毛利是谁？
He's a detective.
他是个侦探
Oh! You mean that famous detective?
就是那个名侦探
Kogoro Mouri?
毛利小五郎？
That's right. I'm Kogoro Mouri, the famous detective.
对 我就是名侦探毛利小五郎
Oh, Mr. Tsuji, let me introduce my family.
啊 辻先生 介绍我的家人给你认识
This is my wife, Eri and my daughter, Ran
我的妻子英理和我女儿小兰
and Conan whom we took in.
还有寄养的柯南
Whom you took in... can't you use another word?
寄养的……没有别的名词了吗？
I'm Tsuji. Mr. Mouri and I were a team
我叫辻弘树 和毛利先生
when we played golf together.
在浦高打高尔夫的时候一组
I remember that
我记得辻先生在为
Mr. Tsuji is preparing for The U.S. Open.
全美高尔夫球公开赛做准备
Yeah. I've been practicing for a year
是啊 为了这个大赛
for that tournament.
一年里一直在练习
This year I'm gonna win the prize!
今年我一定要拿到优胜
I hope you can do it.
祝你好运
Anyhow I still need to relax from time to time.
不过有时也要放松一下
So tomorrow I'll take them on a helicopter ride.
所以明天我会带他们坐直升机
Mr. Tsuji has his own helicopter
辻先生有自己的私人直升机
and has a pilot's license.
还有驾驶执照
Oh right. I plan on flying next Sunday too.
对了 下周日也有飞行
You guys could come if you are free.
有空的话 你们也可以一起来
Really?
真的吗？
That's so romantic.
真浪漫
All right!
太好了
Wait... I'm not familiar with the airplanes.
不……因为我对飞机不太懂
Thanks for your invitation but maybe next time.
谢谢你的邀请 下次吧
Is that so? What a shame.
是吗……真是可惜
How boring.
真无聊
He's Mr. Sawaki.
他是沢木先生
My parents knew him since childhood.
爸妈年轻时的朋友
What's that grape shaped badge?
那个葡萄胸针是什么？
That's the symbol of a sommelier.
那是品酒师的证明
A sommelier is an expert of wine
品酒师就是指像沢木先生一样
like Mr. Sawaki.
葡萄酒的专家
And the thing around his neck is...
他脖子上挂的是……
That's a tastevin,
那个叫做塔斯卡
a tool used for tasting the wine.
是用来试酒的器具
You sure know a lot about wine.
你知道的还真清楚
That's because I have read Mr. Nishina's book.
因为我读过仁科先生的书啊
For example, red wine tastes the best when it's at room temperature
例如红酒是室温
while white and rose wine are best when chilled.
白酒和ROZE最好冰镇
You are right.
你说得没错
But it also depends on people's personal preferences.
但是葡萄酒是可以随个人喜好
That's nice.
很不错啊
Light red wines tastes better when chilled.
淡红酒冰镇会更好喝的
What's important is that the cold can suppress the bitterness in the wine.
最重要的是冰镇能够隐藏涩味
Is that so?
是吗？
I guess Ran is at the age when she's interested in this kind of things.
原来兰也到了对这种事情感兴趣的年龄了
It means we've gotten older as well.
这也证明我们已经老了
That's true.
你说得没错
They seem to get along well with each other, right?
他们两个好像相处的很不错
Conan, you got food on your face.
柯南竟然吃得满嘴都是
It's all right...
没关系的……
Don't move.
不要动哦
A's prediction.
A的预感
Children are so troublesome.
小孩子就是小孩子
It's delicious.
真好喝
The wine and food here
这里的葡萄酒和料理
are as good as before.
和以前一样都没变
Oh... you still remember?
哦……你还记得啊
When we came to this restaurant for the first time ten years ago,
十年前，你和我第一次到这个餐厅时
you gave me a gift.
你送过礼物给我
It was your favorite Ziguba chocolate.
是你最喜欢的Ziguba巧克力
We ate them in the park on the way back home.
我们在回家路上的公园里吃掉了
Yeah.
是啊
Miss Towago!
十和子小姐
Who's that guy?!
那个男人是谁!
Peter Ford a TV news anchor.
皮特·华特 电视台的新闻主播
Damn! Why is she with that guy?
可恶！为什么和那个男人在一起
Who's Miss Towago?
十和子小姐是谁？
The mistress of a club in Ginza.
她是银座俱乐部的妈妈生
She sure takes care of me...
常常受到她的照顾
Excuse me, I'll take my leave.
对不起 我想先走了
It's still very early. Let's have coffee at home.
时间还早 到家里喝杯咖啡吧
Sorry but I have work to do.
对不起 我还有工作要做
Thank you for your hospitality.
谢谢你的招待
Mom mom!
妈妈 妈妈
Dad.
爸爸
No... Miss Towago has left.
啊 十和子小姐走掉了
This man is hopeless.
这个老伯不行了
Please come in.
请进
Juzo Megure.
目暮十三
Juzo is his name.
是 十 三
I see.
是吗
Don't be silly, Genta.
不要傻了 元太
So Inspector Megure's name is Juzo.
原来目暮警部的名字叫做十 三
Mouri, thanks for coming by.
毛利老弟 谢谢你专程来看我
Thank you all.
还有大家
We happened to be going out for a run together.
刚好大家要一起出来跑步
Inspector, how is your injury?
警部 你的伤势如何？
Fortunately, his vital organs were not hit.
幸好没射中要害
So there's no threat to his life.
没有生命危险
But he still needs to stay in the hospital.
但是需要住院
Inspector, why are you still wearing your hat?
警部 为什么你一直戴着帽子呢
It's not important.
这一点不重要啦
I bet his hair is thinning.
一定是很稀疏
Maybe there's a hole on his head.
也许是有个大窟窿
The suspect used a bird hunting crossbow.
犯人所使用的是猎鸟用的箭
We are still trying to figure out if inspector Megure was the target
是专门用来对付目暮警部的
or was he hit while passing.
还是碰巧射中路过的警部
We're investigating it from these two angles.
我们正从这两方面去调查中
Ah Inspector, don't you have a gun with you?
啊 警部叔叔 你身上有佩枪吧
And they still got away?
却被犯人给跑掉了吗？
Why would he bring a gun while going on a jog?
晨跑怎么会带佩枪呢
Also even if I had a gun,
而且就算我有带佩枪
I'm not as good a shot as Mouri.
我也没有毛利那么好的枪法
Huh? My dad is good at shooting?
诶 我爸爸的枪法很准吗
He's one of the best in the force.
在警部里算是一等一的高手
I didn't know he still had some skill.
想不到叔叔还有另一面
By the way, we found something strange
但是在被射中的地方附近
near the place where Inspector Megure was shot.
发现了奇怪的东西
It's this.
就是这个
What is it?
这是什么？
Looks like a paper knife.
好像是纸刀
I seemed to have seen this somewhere.
这个东西好像在哪里见过
Where did I see it?
在哪里呢？
Good morning.
早安
Good morning. The brooch is nice.
早安 那个胸针很漂亮
Sensei, here's your schedule for today.
老师 这是今天的行程
Also this was in the mailbox downstairs.
还有   在楼下的邮箱中收到这个
It's Ziguba.
是Ziguba
It's your favorite chocolate.
是老师最喜欢的巧克力
It has to be him.
原来是他
But it doesn't say who the sender is.
但是没有写明送东西的人
It's fine. I know who the culprit is.
没关系 我知道犯人是谁
Wow...
哇……
Water! Water!
水! 水!
Sensei!
老师！
How's my mom?
我妈妈呢？
Don't worry. We cleaned her stomach in time
请放心   因为马上洗胃
so her life is not in danger.
所以没有生命危险
That's great.
太好了
Was it poison?
是毒药吗？
Yes. We believe it's some sort of pesticide.
是 应该是农药
Mom mom.
妈妈 妈妈
Ran.
兰
Eri.
英理
Honey, you came.
亲爱的 你来了
Are you all right, auntie?
您没事吧 伯母
Conan, you came as well. Thank you. I'm all right.
柯南也来了 谢谢你 我没事
Just to be safe, she should stay in the hospital for observations.
安全起见   今晚最好入院观察
Thank you very much.
那就拜托你了
First the inspector, now it's Eri.
在警部之后连英理也
Is it a coincidence?
会是巧合吗？
Did she collapse as soon as she ate the chocolate?
是正在吃巧克力的时候突然倒下去的吗？
Yes the chocolate was in the firm's mailbox.
是  东西就放在事务所的邮箱里
Ziguba.
Ziguba
Also there's a paper flower!
而且 还有纸制的花
Is it possible that they were hurt by the same person?
难道是    是同样的花吗？
That flower. I seem to have seen it somewhere.
这种花   好像在哪里见过
Where did I see it?
在哪里呢？
Why would such a cautious person like her
但是那么谨慎的人
eat that chocolate?
为什么会吃下巧克力呢？
Because Uncle Mouri irritated Ran's mother
因为在上次的晚餐时
last time when we had dinner together.
老伯惹火了兰的母亲
So she must have thought it was to make amends.
所以错以为是赔罪
I see.
原来如此
It's fixed.
修好了
Who would do such a thing?!
是谁？  这种恶作剧
Professor, don't open the door!
博士   不可以开门
Professor!
博士！
I'm fine. Go after him, Shinichi!
我没事 快去追 新一
But...
但是
Shinichi, I'm telling you to go!
新一   我叫你追
Got it!
我知道了
Where did he go?
往哪边去了呢？
The houses of Ayumi and Genta are on the left.
左边是步美和元太的家
All right.
决定了
Conan.
柯南
A racing motorcycle?
赛车型的摩托车？
What is a racing motorcycle?
赛车型的摩托车是什么？
That one! That one is a racing motorcycle!
就是那个   那个就是赛车型的摩托车
- Genta. - Conan!
元太     柯南
Roger! He did turn left.
明白了 真的是左边
Conan, he made a turn by the gas station.
柯南 他在加油站处转弯了
Got it! I'll take a shortcut!
明白了 抄近路
All right! Found him!
好 找到他了
I won't let you get away! I won't let you get away with this!
不让你逃走 绝不让你逃走
Are you all right, madam?
不要紧吧 老婆婆
Thank you.
谢谢你
What's this?
这是？
So that's what it is. I get it now!
原来如此 我知道了
Playing cards?
扑克牌？
Yes, the suspect is committing the crimes
对    犯人是根据扑克牌的顺序
in the order of the Face Cards.
去作案的
The first one who got attacked was Inspector Megure.
最先受到攻击的是目暮警官
His name is Juzo right? (Juzo sounds like thirteen in Japanese.)
他的名字是    十三吧
Thirteen refers to the king of spades.
所以是黑桃K
The sword in the king's hand
这个国王手里拿的剑
is exactly like the one which was left at the crime scene.
和现场留下的一模一样
Then it's Ran's mother Eri Kisaki.
然后是兰的母亲妃英理
Kisaki means Queen.
妃就是Queen
Thus the queen of spades.
也就是黑桃Q
The flower which the queen is holding
这个王妃拿的花
is just like the one with the chocolate box.
和巧克力上的一样
They are exactly the same.
真的完全一样
But what does Hiroshi Agasa have to do with eleven?
但是  阿笠博士和十一有什么关系呢？
We call him Hiroshi Agasa.
博士叫阿笠博士
The word shi could be divided into the words ten and one.
士是由十和一组成的
Eleven refers to Jack of spades
所以是黑桃J
which means the soldier.
它的意思是士兵
That's why he has the sword-like object.
这种类似剑的东西
They are the same. You are right.
一样    没有错
But why the playing cards?
但是为什么是扑克牌呢？
Also why does it have to be spades?
而且一定是黑桃吗？
The suit of spades represent death.
黑桃代表死亡
Likewise hearts represent love
同样的   红桃代表爱
diamonds represent money
方块代表金钱
and clubs represent happiness.
梅花代表幸福
So the suspect wants to kill the people
那么犯人想利用扑克牌
whose name have the number from one to thirteen
在名字里有一到十三的人
in descending order?
按顺序杀害吗？
Also these are people related to Uncle Mouri.
而且是与伯父有关的人
But who would do such a thing?
到底是谁呢？
The only thing we know is the plate number of the motorcycle.
唯一知道的摩托车的牌照
It was stolen.
可以查出是失车
Inspector! What are you doing here?
警部    你怎么会来这里？
I heard that after Eri was attacked,
听说在英理被袭击后
even Professor Agasa was attacked.
连博士也遭到袭击了
But you haven't recovered yet.
但是你的伤还没好
I already got stitches. I'm fine.
缝了针    没事的
I heard that the suspect
我已经听说了
might be Jo Murakami.
犯人有可能是村上丈
Jo Murakami?
村上丈？
Who's that?
他是什么人？
He used to be a card dealer.
以前是个牌桌的发牌师
Ten years ago he was arrested for murder
十年前因为杀人事件被捕
and was just released a week ago.
一个星期前出狱
A card dealer?
牌桌的牌师？
A person that passes out playing cards to gamblers.
在扑克牌桌上为客人发牌的
This is what Jo Murakami looked like ten years ago.
这就是十年前的村上丈
Jo Murakami. If it really is him,
村上丈   如果真是他的话
he does have a reason to hate me.
他的确很恨我
Why?
为什么？
Because I'm the one who arrested him.
因为是我逮捕他的
How could he do that? Isn't it only natural
怎么能这样    警察抓犯人
for a policeman to catch a criminal?
是天经地义的
You are not wrong but.
虽然如此
I've heard about that too.
那件事我也听说了
If I'm not mistaken after he was sent to jail...
我记得那个男人进到监狱之后
Shiratori! That's enough.
白鸟  那件事不要再提了
But why didn't Murakami come for me directly?
但是为什么村上不直接来找我
Since I'm the one he wants to take revenge on then...
如果复仇的话应该直接来
Perhaps he wants you to suffer
可能是想折磨你
and watch you in pain.
让你痛苦下去
Does anyone you know
在伯父认识的人之中
whose name have the word ten?
名字里有没有十字的人
That person could be the next target!
下一个被攻击的人就是他
Ten ten.
十   十
Miss Towago!
十合子小姐
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Mr. Mouri.
毛利先生
Miss Towago, I'm glad you are fine!
十合子小姐  幸好你没事
What do you mean? What happened?
没事？发生什么事了？
Officer Shiratori what were you going to say at the hospital?
请问白鸟警官在医院想说什么呢？
The thing about that Murakami.
就是那个村上的事情
I found out after doing some digging.
因为调查才知道的
I heard from a senior officer.
这是听警察的前辈讲的
Ten years ago Mr. Mouri who was still a junior police
十年前还是初级警察的毛利先生
worked with Inspector Megure
和中央警局的目暮警官
who was also a low-rank officer.
当时还是警部署
Anyway they caught Murakami together.
总之他们两个把杀人犯村上丈抓住了
While Jo Murakami was giving his statement
在录口供时
he asked to use the restroom.
村上说想上厕所
Mr. Mouri and Inspector Megure
毛利先生和警部
asked another officer to take him to the restroom.
让其他警员带他到厕所去
Then they started to smoke outside the interrogation room.
两个人在审讯室前抽烟
At that time, your mother brought you there
那时兰的母亲带着你来
to bring some spare clothes for Mr. Mouri.
帮毛利先生带换洗衣物
That's when it happened.
那时发生了意外
Murakami caught that officer off guard
村上乘着警员不备
and took his gun.
抢走了警枪
I remember now.
我想起来了
At that time.
我就在那个时候
Prepare a car for me!
快给我准备车子
Or else, I'll send this woman to hell.
不然我就让这个女人到地狱去
Mom!
妈妈
Don't come over!
不可以到这边来!
Mouri.
毛利
What's wrong? You look lost.
怎么了  在那里发呆
It's nothing.
没事
So Uncle Mouri shot Auntie Eri?
这么说  是伯父开枪射伯母？
I had forgotten all about it.
我已经忘记了
That must be a terrible memory for you.
这对兰小姐是个不好的回忆
But... but why did my dad shoot my mom?
但是  但是爸爸为什么会开枪呢？
I think it's because he was confident in his ability to shoot a gun
我想可能是他对自己的枪法很有自信
and believed that he could avoid the hostage and hit the criminal.
自信能够避开人质而射中犯人
But in the end, it hit your mom.
但子弹却射中你母亲
Opening fire when the hostage's life was at risk
当时在警局对不理会人质而开枪
was a serious mistake at that time.
是很严重的问题
Not long after that,
那件事不久
your father quit his job as an officer.
你父亲便辞去了警察的工作
Hi.
Hi
Ran, it's been a while.
兰   好久不见了
Shinichi.
新一
I heard from Hiroshi Agasa that
我听博士讲了
things have turned serious.
好像变成了很大事
It's more than just a serious matter! Where are you?
不止是很大的事    你在哪里？
Can you come back right away?
快点回来吧
Sorry I have a lot of things to deal with.
对不起  我这边也有很多事情要处理
So I can't go back so soon.
所以短期内是回不去了
Really?
是吗？
Don't sound so disappointed.
别发出这么失望的声音
I heard the whole story from Hiroshi Agasa and other officers.
我也听了博士和警员说的大概
I'll call you when I have some ideas.
如果有什么事情再打电话给你
If it were you, would you open fire?
如果是新一的话会开枪吗？
I finally knew
我终于明白了
why my mom left my dad.
妈妈离开爸爸的理由
So Uncle Mouri shot your mom.
那个笨蛋对你母亲
He shouldn't have done that no matter how confident he was.
就算对自己的枪法很有信心
I feel that I can no longer trust my father anymore.
我开始越来越不信任父亲了
Shinichi, you wouldn't do the same thing, would you?
新一是绝对不会做这种事的  对吧？
I don't know. I'm not sure.
不知道  我也不清楚
Though it is a fact that Uncle Mouri shot Auntie Eri,
只是伯父射中伯母虽然是事实
he might have another reason.
但不一定是这个原因
What do you mean? I don't understand.
什么意思？我不理解
That's all I can say for now.
我能说的也只有这些
You have to pull yourself together Ran. Bye.
你要提起精神  兰  再见
Wait.
等等
Shinichi! Shinichi!
新一    新一
Another reason...
真正的原因
Inspector, I'll go in through the emergency exit.
警部  我从非常口进入
Wait, Mouri!
等等  毛利
He's always full of energy when it comes to a beautiful woman.
对方是美人   他就那么认真
Uncle Mouri still hasn't come back.
大叔还是没有回来
Also why did Murakami leave so many clues
另外那个村上为什么要留下证据
that point to him?
让别人知道是他做的
Is he trying to challenge Uncle Mouri and the others?
难道他是想挑战老伯他们吗？
But how did he find out about
但是村上在服刑中
Uncle Mouri's friends in jail?
是如何调查老伯的朋友的呢？
He even knows about Ran's mom's favorite chocolate.
他连兰的母亲最喜欢的巧克力都知道
Hiroki Tsuji.
辻弘树
Tsuji?!
辻？ ！
Hiroki Tsuji? The golf player?
辻弘树？ 那个高尔夫选手？
Conan noticed it.
是柯南发现的
Mr. Tsuji's name has the word ten.
辻先生的名字里也有十字
Tsuji... it does have it!
辻...真的有个十字
I called his home
刚才打电话到辻先生家
but his family said that he went to the airport 30 minutes ago.
家人说30分钟前去了机场
Understood. Contact him
我知道了   你去帮我通知
and tell him not to get on the helicopter.
叫他们别上直升机
Conan, let's go over too.
柯南  我们也过去吧
Huh?
哎？
We're going, Mouri!
要走了  毛利
To where? Are we having breakfast?
走？去吃早餐？
Dad!
爸爸
What are you doing here?!
你们来这干什么？
What do you mean?
来干什么？
We were also involved in this incident.
我们也是事件的关系者
I am your daughter.
因为我是爸爸的女儿
So people around Mr. Mouri
所以与毛利先生有关的人
were attacked one after another?
一个个的被攻击了吗
Yes, from thirteen to eleven.
对  而且是从十三到十一
So you are the next one in danger.
所以接下来的你也有危险
I hope you could give up flying the helicopter today.
希望你今天放弃直升机驾驶
I'll be fine. If you are worried about me,
没事的  如果不放心的话
why don't you and Mr. Mouri join me?
就请警部和毛利先生一起上来吧
No, I don't like things that can fly.
不    我对天上飞的东西
May I know where you are flying to?
请问你今天预定往哪里飞？
Airport Tungtu.
德机场
But we'll go sightseeing while we're at it.
在途中会绕一绕圈子
When did you apply for the flight?
你是何时提出的飞行申请？
I think... I did it at the Flight Management Service the day before yesterday.
我记得是...前天在飞行管理处
Inspector, I think Murakami might be waiting at Tungtu Airport.
警部   我想村上会在德机场等着
Fine, you should drive to the airport first.
好  你开车先去德机场
Yes, sir.
是
Mouri! Just to be safe,
毛利  为了预防万一
you and I will take the helicopter!
你和我坐直升机
Ran, I understand your feelings.
兰  我理解你的心情
But this is as far as you two are going.
但是请到此为止
But...
但是...
Fine.
我知道了
Inspector, I think I should take the car with Shiratori.
警部  我想和白鸟一起坐车
Are you trying to run away on your own?
难道你想一个人逃走吗？
No, I never thought of that.
不  我没这么想过
Inspector, I don't want to die!
警部  我还不想死
We'll die together!
要死也是一起死
No, we are really going to die!
不要  真的会死
Well, I'll be on my way.
那么我先走了
Conan, let's...
柯南  我们也...
Where are you? Don't tell me?!
你在哪里？难道说？！
One sheep... two sheep...
一只羊....两只羊...
Is that a chant which could prevent us from falling down?
那是祈求不要掉下去的咒语吗？
Conan?!
柯南？
When did you...
你什么时候...
I've always wanted to
只要一次就够了
sit in the co-pilot seat.
能够坐在副驾驶座上
Welcome to my helicopter.
欢迎乘坐我的直升机
We'll pass by Beika City where you live later.
我们也要经过你住的米花
All right!
太棒了！
There's nothing we can do. We can't turn back now.
没办法   现在也不能回头
If you don't listen to me, I'll throw you out the window!
但是如果不听话  小心被丢出去
Everything seems normal.
一点异常也没有
What are you looking for? You don't always have the chance to take the helicopter.
你在看什么？好不容易上一次直升机
You should look at the view outside.
应该看看外边的景色
Is something wrong?
怎么了？
Nothing.
没事
You used some eye drops earlier, right?
你刚才点了眼药水了吧？
Do you always do that?
你常常点吗？
Yes, every time when I drive or fly the helicopter.
是  开车和开直升机的时候
We are about to reach Beika City.
就快到米花了
You're right!
真的
Mouri, I can see your house.
毛利  可以看到你家
I don't want to look!!
我不想看!!
What's the matter?
怎么了？
The sunlight is too bright for my eyes. I can't open my eyes!
阳光太刺眼了   我睁不开眼
What did you say?!!
你说什么！！
Could it be... the eye drops?
难道...就是那眼药水
Which means...
这么说...
Mister, we drifting to the left!
叔叔  我们偏向左边了
Mouri, can you fly the helicopter?
毛利   你会驾驶直升机吗？
How's that even possible?
我怎么可能会？
It's impossible to continue flying like this.
这样继续驾驶是不可能的
Is there somewhere we can land?
不知道哪里可以降落
Beika Central Primary School!
米花中央小学校
Okay!
好
What are you doing?
做什么？
We are going to land the helicopter.
我们要进行降落
Please control the other parts!
请叔叔帮忙操纵其他机器
You fool, are you trying to get us all killed?
笨蛋  你想害死我们吗？
It's fine. I practiced a lot on a flight simulator when I was a kid.
没问题  小时候开过无数次的模拟飞行
But you're still a kid.
你现在还是个小孩子呀
Mr. Tsuji, the helicopter is going to crush if things continue like this.
辻先生   这样下去也只有坠机
Please help me!
帮帮忙吧
I understand. Let's give it a try.
我知道了  试试吧
Are you serious?
来真的呀
Altitude 300 feet and the speed is 40 knots. I am ready.
高度300   速度40   可以了
All right, here we go!
要开始了
Altitude 200 feet and the speed is 30 knots.
高度200   速度30
Step on the accelerator on the right.
踩右边的油门
We're going straight!
固定方向
We are 500 feet from the school!
距离500
Genta, Genta, can you hear me?
元太  元太  听见了吗
Conan.
柯南
A helicopter is making an emergency landing.
现在让直升机进行迫降
Tell everybody to leave!
叫大家离开
A helicopter?
直升机？
Everybody, run!
大家快逃
The helicopter is going to fall down!
直升机要掉下来了
I won't let that happen.
我不会让它掉下去的
We're rotating left! Press the right pedal harder!
直升机向左旋转  踩右边的刹车
Be ready to land.
进入降落准备
It really crashed.
真的掉下来了
Is Conan really in there?
柯南真的在里面吗？
We survived.
得救了
Conan.
柯南
Are you all right, Mr. Tsuji?
你没事吧  辻先生
It is leaking fuel!
漏油了
What?
什么？
The helicopter exploded.
爆炸了
Aren't helicopters expensive?
直升机很贵吧？
That type of helicopter is worth at least ten million yen.
那种机型至少一千万
I can buy so many pork cutlets with that amount of money.
那是炸猪排饭的几倍呀？
Luckily everyone's fine.
幸好大家都没事
But Professor,
但是博士
Conan is so unfair.
柯南好坏
He flew a real helicopter.
自己操纵真正的直升机
You missed the point!
现在不是讲这个问题的时候
I almost died!
我差一点就死掉了
About that.
关于这件事情
The eyed rops which Mr. Tsuji used is supposed to be vitamin drops
辻先生所点的眼药水
but was replaced with mydriatics.
维他命药水换成了酸导剂
Mydriatics?
酸导剂？
It's a kind of drug which could dilate one's pupils
用来治疗假性近视
to treat pseudomyopia.
使瞳孔放大的药水
I see.
原来如此
That's why Mr. Tsuji
所以辻先生
found the sunlight blinding.
才会因为阳光太刺眼
But the eye drops Mr. Tsuji put in his eyes were used to treat glaucoma.
但是辻先生点的是治疗青光眼所用的
Glaucoma?
青光眼？
What's the difference?
有什么不一样吗？
The eye drops used to treat pseudomyopia will take effect in 5 minutes and wears off quickly.
假性近视的眼药水5分钟见效,恢复也很快
But the one used to treat glaucoma will take effect in 10 minutes
但是青光眼的要10分钟见效
while lasting longer.
要恢复也要很长时间
How long?
多长时间？
It depends on the patient's condition.
依个人的体制
Usually it would last ten days to two weeks.
10天到2个星期瞳孔会一直放大
It will take that long?
会那么久？
That means the U.S Open that starts on Thursday...
那么星期四开始的全美公开赛
He'll have to cancel.
只有放弃了
When did the culprit replace the eyedrops?
那犯人是什么时候换走药水的呢？
About that.
关于这件事
After Mr. Tsuji pulled out of the garage,
辻先生今天早上从车库把车子开出来后
he used the eyedrops in the car.
在车子里点过眼药水
After that, he heard the sound of glass breaking.
在那之后  听见了打破玻璃的声音
Then he left the eyedrops on the central console
把眼药水放在驾驶盘上
and went back to his house.
回到屋子里去
Someone seemed to have broken the glass with a stone.
好像是被人用石块砸坏的
A stone? Like what happened to Professor Agasa!
石头  和阿笠博士那时一样
At that time, Mr. Tsuji thought it was just a child's prank.
那时的辻先生以为是小孩子捣乱
After he told someone to clean the place, he went back to his car.
叫人清理后  就回车里了
The one who threw the stone must be the culprit.
丢石头的就是犯人
He must have replaced the eyedrops when Mr. Tsuji went back to the house.
眼药水一定是趁辻先生回房的时候放的
Yes, most likely.
我想是吧
Inspector,
警部
it has to be Jo Murakami.
犯人是村上丈没错
We found this.
我们发现了这个
Ten of spades.
黑桃十
Mouri, his next target is nine!
毛利  下一个目标是九
Do you have any friends whose name has the number 9?
有没有名字里有九的朋友
I can't think of any.
这个我还没想到
But I do know someone whose name has eight.
如果是八的话就有了
Eight?
八？
Kohei Sawaki.
就是沢木公平
His last name is Kouhei.
他的名字是公平
The word eight is inside the word 'Kou'.
公字上面就是个八
All right, let's go find Mr. Sawaki.
好 我们去找沢木先生
So, this Murakami guy
那么那个叫村上的人
attacked the people who know Mr. Mouri
为了报复毛利先生
one after another
所以对毛利先生熟识的人
in order to take his revenge on Mr. Mouri?
一个接一个的攻击吗
Yes.
是的
But, Mr. Mouri, you seem pretty calm.
但是毛利先生好像很镇定
Because the number in my name is five.
因为我是五
So it'll take a while before he comes for me.
所以轮到我还要一段时间
It's wine.
是葡萄酒
That's a wine cooler.
那叫做存酒室
It keeps wine at the right temperature.
把葡萄酒保存在一定的温度下
There are so many wines.
好多的葡萄酒啊
Sawaki has a plantation in his hometown.
沢木老弟的老家种果树
At his home there, they have hundreds of bottles of wine.
那里面有数百瓶葡萄酒
Am I right?
是吧
Yes, it's because I'm planning to start my own business.
是的  还有为了以后自己开店
I like wine a lot too.
我也很喜欢葡萄酒
Can I take a look at those wines?
可不可以让我看看
Please.
请
The floor is damaged.
这里有缺口
I hope you are not injured. I dropped a box there a while ago.
没事吧  那是以前撞到箱子
Conan, you're not wearing slippers. Be careful.
柯南 你没穿拖鞋 要小心些
Margaux, Lafite, Haut Brion.
马卢  拉迪  欧不利翁
The wines here are all of high-class.
全是名贵的葡萄酒
Come to think of it, what's the name of it?
我记得那个   叫什么名字
Your favourite wine. It's called Chateau...
沢木先生最喜欢的     莎木
You have Chateau Perse?
你有莎木贝多斯
Chateau Perse?
莎木贝多斯？
The wine which Poirot drank in the movie "Death on the Nile".
在谢多事件里波罗喝的酒
I had one. But I drank it the other day.
有 但是在不久前被我喝掉了
But you said you had to wait for a few years
但是听你讲能够喝掉它
to drink it?
要等数年才行
Well, I couldn't wait any longer...
因为我等不及了
Mr. Sawaki, let's talk about wine some other time.
沢木先生  下次再听你讲酒的事
Can you tell us about your schedule for today
可以讲一讲你今天的行程吗？
Do you know Katsuyoshi Asahi?
你们知道旭胜义先生吗
He owned a lot of hotels in Tokyo.
在东京经营不少的酒店
A real businessman.
是个实业家
Mr. Asahi asked me a favor once,
旭先生因为有事拜托我
that's when I met him.
所以见过一次面
I heard he's building a new entertainment plaza
听说在这次东京湾内的海洋公园
in the Ocean Park at Tokyo Bay.
要开间新的娱乐广场
Yes. He asked me to take charge of one of the restaurants there.
是的  他说那里的一间餐厅要让我管
I'll meet him at three o'clock to discuss about that.
因为这件事  我跟他约在三点见面
Katsuyoshi Asahi.
旭胜义
Asahi.
旭
Wait.
等等
It's nine. The word 'Asahi' has the number nine.
是九   旭字里有九
So he's the next target.
这么说下一个被攻击的人是他
But he only asked me to find his cat at that time.
但是他只是拜托我找宠物猫
I can't say he's a friend.
并不算是朋友
Maybe Murakami doesn't think so.
也许村上不这么认为
Either way, let's go to meet Mr. Asahi
我们就顺便做沢木先生的保镖
since we're guarding Mr. Sawaki.
去见一见旭先生吧
What do you say, Mr. Sawaki?
可以吗   沢木先生
I'm fine with that.
我没问题
So, Ran and Conan...
那么兰和柯南
We are going. Conan and I are going with you.
要去  我和柯南也要去
Don't be kidding!
别开玩笑了
This is not a game!
这可不是儿戏
That's right. People were attacked because of my dad!
是呀   有人因为爸爸而遭到攻击
How can I stay at home and wait for the news?
我怎么能静静的在家里等消息
Ran.
兰
That's the Crystal Plaza...
那就是乐乐广场……
What a
怎么会有
flashy building.
这么豪华的场所
What a reckless driver.
真是粗鲁的家伙
A little bit outside the line.
偏了一点
But not bad I suppose.
但是也算不错了
Hey! That was very dangerous, lady!
喂！很危险的 小姐
What?
什么事？
Well...
那个……
Miss Nana, you are here.
奈奈小姐 你也来啦
Shishido, you were also invited by Mr. Asahi.
宍户老师也受到旭先生的邀请啊
Excuse me, Miss, who are you?
很抱歉 小姐 你是谁
Huh, you don't know me?
诶 大叔你不认识我？
She's Nana Osanai. A model, Inspector.
她是模特小山内奈奈小姐 警部
A super model actually.
是个超级模特
From the left,
那边的三人从左面开始
My. Nishina, the writer,
作家仁科先生
Mr. Shishido, the photographer,
摄影家宍户先生
and...
还有
I'm Peter Ford.
我是皮特 华特
You two are with the police, right?
那边两位是警方的人吧
And you must be the famous detective, Kogoro Mouri.
而另一位是名侦探毛利小五郎
Ah! You are that famous detective?
啊！你就是那位有名的侦探先生啊
This is the first time I'm seeing you in the flesh.
我第一次看到真人
Mr. Shishido, please take a photo of us.
宍户老师 帮我拍照
Hey! Weren't you very angry with her just now?
喂！你刚才的怒气到哪里去了
This is Mr. Sawaki, a sommelier.
这位是品酒师沢木先生
Ran who is Mr. Mouri's daughter
毛利先生的女儿 兰小姐
and Conan Edogawa.
还有江户川柯南
You are the lady who asked me to write more delicious books.
你就是那位请再写好味的书的小姐
You still remember me?
你还记得我
I always remember beautiful wines and ladies.
葡萄酒和女性只要是漂亮的我都会记下来的
All right, all right.
是是是
Is everyone here invited by Mr. Asahi?
大家都是被旭先生请来的吗？
He asked to meet me at three.
他约我三点
Me too.
我也是三点
Inspector, is there anything wrong with that?
警部先生 难道有事件发生吗？
Actually.
其实是
It's almost three o'clock. Let's go.
快要三点了 我们快走吧
You are right. Let's go to the restaurant first.
你说得对 我们先到餐厅去吧
Hey! The four people here.
哎！集合在这里的四人
Do we have to take the monorail
要到乐乐广场
to get to the Crystal Plaza?
一定要坐缆车吗？
There's no driver.
没有驾驶员
It seems that we only need to push this button.
好像只要按下钮就行了
The view is great.
这真是不错
Mr. Nishina, you don't like
仁科先生对空中跑的东西
things that fly too, huh?
也是很棘手吗？
No, I'm scared of the water.
不 我不喜欢水
I feel like I'm going to be drowned.
好像会被淹没的感觉
Oh... we all have our own fears.
啊……每个人都有不同的习惯……
Although it's true that Uncle Mouri shot your mom,
伯父用枪射中伯母这是事实
but he might have another reason.
但并不一定就是真正的原因
Haha... it's like we are in an aquarium.
哈哈……就像是在水族馆一样
It truely is an underwater restaurent!
不愧是海中餐厅
Wow, It's a Ferrari F40.
哇 法拉利40
How did they get it in here?
是怎么运进来的呢？
Where's Mr. Asahi?
旭先生呢？
That's strange. The guests are all here but the host...
真奇怪 招待客人到这里……
Did Murakami already...
莫非已经被村上给……
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Did Murakami already what?
莫非让村上给
That's right, I need to explain this to you guys.
对了 这件事必须说明一下
Inspector, I'll go inside to have a look.
警部 我到里面去查看一下
I'll go with you.
我也一起
Please do.
拜托你们了
Please find a place to sit down, everyone!
大家就在这附近找个位置坐下吧
This is the emergency exit.
非常口在这里
Only this door is locked.
只有这里是锁着的
I see.
原来如此
I didn't find anything unusual.
一点异状都没有
So I am the six.
这么说六就是指我了
Why?
为什么
Because the word 'Shishido' has the number six inside.
因为宍户里面有个六字
It does.
的确是
The other three people also have numbers in their names.
其他的三人名字里面也有数字
What?
什么！
Miss Nana, your number is seven.
奈奈小姐的数字是七
Mr. Nishina, yours is two.
仁科先生是二
Mr. Ford's name sounds like four in English.
华特先生是英文的四
I see. So now we have all the numbers here
原来如此 这样除了三和一
except for three and one.
其他的都齐全了
Three is here too. He's right in front of you.
三也在这里 就在你面前
Hey! You mean.
喂！莫非
My name is Ninzaburo Shiratori.
我的名字是白鸟任三郎
Nin... zaburo!
任……三郎！
But we don't have the number one.
但是没有一
Shinichi!
新一！
What if the number one is for Shinichi?
莫非一就是指新一
Kuro? Are you saying that Kudo will come?
工藤！你是说工藤也会来吗
No, it's just an assumption.
不是的 我只是这么觉得
That's right, if my body hadn't been shrunk,
的确 如果不是我变小了
I would have came out of curiosity.
一定也对这件事情很感兴趣而跟来
So I am that number one.
看来一真的是指我了
I'd like to ask everyone a question just in case.
为了预防万一我想请问大家
Does anyone of you know Jo Murakami?
你们和村上丈有什么关系吗
How could I know someone like that?
怎么可能会有关系 和那种男人
Me neither.
我也没有
I do.
我有
Before I became a food writer, I used to write crime fictions.
成为美食作家之前是写犯罪小说
So I did some research on Murakami's case before.
有研究过村上的事件
Me too. I've taken photos of Murakami
我也有 在上次的犯人写真集里
when I worked on an album of criminals.
我拍过村上的照片
Did anything happen at that time?
那个时候有没有发生什么事情？
No.
没有
Miss Nana, was there something?
奈奈小姐有什么事情吗？
That man was freed from prison six days ago, right?
那个人在六天前出狱的吧
Yeah.
是啊
Then it doesn't matter.
那就没有关系了
Come on... why is everybody so serious?
讨厌……大家变得这么认真
Let's not talk about this.
别再讲这件事了
Hey, you!
喂 就是你吧！
Aren't you the one that recommended that restaurent in Paris?
在书上推销巴黎餐厅的作家
The food at the restaurant you recommended
那上面推荐的餐厅
tasted terrible!
东西非常的难吃
Do you really know what good food is?
你真的了解味道吗
Excuse me!
真失礼
Of course I know.
我当然了解
Then prove it.
那么就拿出证明来
Prove it?
证明？
This is my gift to Mr. Asahi.
我是想带来送给旭先生当礼物的
Can you tell me where this wine is from?
就让你猜猜这是哪里的葡萄酒
Are you testing me?
要测试我的能力吗
I'll take the challenge.
我接受
This full bodied red wine
这种在嘴里浓郁的香味
tastes very smooth.
喝下去也很滑
This is Emperor Napoleon's favorite, Chambertin.
是旧法国国王拿破仑最爱的香榭
This is hilarious!
真是太好笑了
How could I buy such a cheap wine as a gift?
我怎么可能买这么便宜的酒送人
Then this is...
那这是
You're a sommelier, right?
你是品酒师吧
Yes...
是……
Tell that tasteless man the real answer.
你告诉那个没有品味的男人答案
It's Monteloro Murrpan.
是蒙特罗的MURRPAN
Correct!
答对了
How's that possible! This is Monteloro?
怎么可能！这是蒙特罗
The Monteloro wines of good quality
在蒙特罗里面把品质好的红酒
will give a taste and flavor close to a Brenos
保存之后 就能成为像布宜诺思
if perserved well.
那种特级的味道和香味出现
You get it now, right?
这样你认输了吧
You should stop calling yourself a gourmet.
还是快拆掉你美食专家的招牌吧
Even I want to have some wine now.
连我也想喝红酒了
Let's drink together.
那么大家一起喝吧
I'll bring it here.
我去拿过来
I want some beers.
我想喝啤酒
Where's the kitchen?
厨房在哪里
Over there.
在那边
Kid, you should lead the way.
小子 带我去吧
Okay.
嗯
Who are you calling a kid.
谁是小子啊
It's here, it's here.
有了有了
You'll be happy to hear this, kid.
你可以高兴了 小子
There's juice too.
因为里面也有果汁
Really, this is great.
真的吗 太高兴了
Stop calling me kid.
别再叫我小子了
Sister Ran.
小兰姐姐
Thanks.
谢谢你
Oh no.
不好
Mr. Sawaki is right, it does taste great.
沢木先生说得对 的确很好喝
Mr. Sawaki, would you like another glass?
沢木先生 要不要再来一杯
It's fine. I'll have some mineral water.
不用了 我喝矿泉水就好了
Thanks.
谢谢你
Uncle Mouri, you are not going to drink beer?
叔叔不喝啤酒吗？
Of course not! I don't know
当然！因为我不知道村上
when Murakami will attack us.
什么时候会来偷袭
Inspector, here you are.
警部 这个给你
Conan, I'm not thirsty, you can have this.
柯南 我不渴 这个给你吧
It's fine. I'll get another one.
没关系 我再去拿
Hey! Don't run around!
喂！别乱跑啊
Mineral water is in the lower drawer of the fridge.
矿泉水在冰箱的下层抽屉里
Ah, thanks.
啊 谢谢你
That seasoning is rare,
因为是很稀有的调味料
so I thought I'd give it a try.
所以我想试试味道
Conan, you are looking for the juice on the top level, are you?
柯南想要的果汁是在上面吗？
Yes.
嗯
Anyway, Mr. Asahi is so slow.
不过旭先生也真是慢
What on earth is he doing now?
他到底在干什么呢？
Huh? What happened?
什么啊！发生什么事情了
I'm just joking.
开玩笑的
Seriously.
真是的
Mr. Ford, please don't joke around at a time like this!
华特先生 这种时候别拿这个开玩笑
May I ask why you guys are invited here?
请问为什么要叫你们来呢？
His secretary called me.
听说是他的秘书打来的
Mr. Asahi is a fan of mine
因为旭先生是我的崇拜者
and maybe he wants to have a chat with me.
想和我见面聊天吧
Perhaps he wants me to
大概是想找我
advertise this place for him.
替他为这个建筑做宣传吧
I also received a call from his secretary.
我也是接到了秘书的电话
The secretary pretty much said the same thing.
邀请的话完全一样
Unlike you guys, I got a present.
而我还得到礼物
Check this nail polish.
你们看 这个指甲油
It's French and very expensive.
法国产的 非常贵的哦
Mr. Nishina, is it the same for you?
仁科先生也是一样吗？
Yes!
是的
What are you doing, Miss Nana?
你在做什么 奈奈小姐
Painting the cork with the nail polish.
在红酒的软木塞上用指甲油画
It's cute, isn't it?
很可爱吧
What's that, a civet?
那是什么 狸猫吗？
You're so mean. It's a cat.
老师真讨厌 是猫啊
Mr. Sawaki, this is for you.
沢木先生 是给您的
It just fell on the ground.
掉在地上了
Kohei Sawaki, I may be late.
沢木公平先生 也许我会迟到
Your favourite wine is on M-18 Wine Rack in the wine cellar.
请到酿酒室第M－18的酒架上
Please bring it for everyone to drink.
拿你喜欢的红酒出来给大家喝
The key is in the envelope by the cash register.
钥匙在收银机边上的信封里面
Thank you,
拜托你了
Katsuyoshi Asahi.
旭胜义
Huh? Was that note there
啊？刚才捡果汁的时候
when I tried to pick the juice?
有那张纸条吗？
I want to see the wine cellar here too.
我想看看酿酒室
Me too.
我也想看看
I'd like to know what kinds of wines are there.
我也想看看那里到底有些什么葡萄酒
So, let's go together.
那么 大家一起去吧
This is...
这是……
This is grand!
真是壮观
It's so cold.
好冷
No! This place is actually a bit hot.
不！应该是有些热
Wine should be kept at a temperature between 10 to 14 degrees.
在十到十四度的环境中保存葡萄酒才是最理想的
The temperature here is seventeen degree,
这里是十七度
which means it's a bit warm here.
有点偏暖
Inspector, please come here.
警部 请过来看
All of these are rare wines!
全部都是特级葡萄酒
La Romanee-Conti, La Tache, Le Pin, Cote Rotie.
罗马迪 拉塔周 鲁巴 科多骆帝 普洛洛美尼
How amazing!
实在太棒了
M-18.
M－18
Over there.
就是那个
Watch out!
危险！
A short arrow.
是短箭
Uncle! Officer!
叔叔！警部！
It's the same thing which hit me.
这是和射中我的一样的东西
Inspector!
警部！
The crossbow is here.
弓放在这里
Eight of spades.
黑桃八
That means Murakami set this up
真的是村上放的
and that note was also his.
那张危险的纸条也是村上弄的
If so,
如果真的是这样
why did Murakami skip nine
为什么村上要跳过九
and attack Sawaki who represents eight directly?
攻击八的沢木先生?
Could it be?
莫非
Inspector, let's leave this place first.
警部 我们先离开这里去避难吧
What? It's closed?
啊？关起来了？
Isn't this the entrance?
入口不是在这里吗
Yeah, it was.
不 入口是在这里没错
If we are leaving, I should grab my coat first.
如果要回去的话 我想去拿外套
Go ahead.
请
Ah...
啊……
Mr. Asahi!
旭先生！
The nine of spades. It has to be Murakami.
黑桃九 果然是村上
Inspector, the door is controlled by computers.
警部 这扇门由电脑控制
I can't open it.
打不开
What are you talking about?!
你说什么！
I'll call for help.
那么利用这个吧
No, there's no signal here.
不行 收不到讯号
The phone line's been cut. Shoot!
被切断了 可恶
Inspector, I'll go check the emergency exit!
警部 我去看看非常口
What? It's blocked with concrete.
什么 用混凝土封住了
It's all your fault!
都是你
You're the one that dragged us into this!
是你让我们这些无关的人扯进去
That's right! What are you going to do with this?
是啊 你要怎么负责
If Murakami didn't change the order,
如果村上没有改变顺序的话
then the next victim will be you, Miss Nana.
下一个应该就是奈奈小姐你了
Cut it out. Why should I be attacked by
不要再说了 为什么我要被
a man I don't know?
那种不认识的人给袭击呢
But something is bothering you, right?
但是你也有点怀疑吧
Because just now you said.
因为刚才
That man was freed from jail six days ago, right?
那个人在六天前才出狱的吧
Yes.
是的
That's not relevant to this matter.
但是那一点关系都没有
We'll decide if it is relevant or not.
有没有关系 由我们来决定
Please tell us.
请讲出来吧
Three months ago,
在三个月前
I guess so.
好像是啊
Though I didn't hit the man,
虽然没有撞到
I still drove away because I was too scared.
但是因为太害怕所以逃走了
A motorcyclist? Was it a racing motorcycle?
骑摩托车的人呢？赛车型的吗？
No, it was a normal motorcycle.
不是 是普通的摩托车
Inspector, what Miss Nana said
警部 奈奈小姐所讲的
has nothing to do with this incident.
和这次的事件无关
The most important thing now is getting out of this place.
现在最重要的是想办法离开
You are right. Let's split up to find a way out.
你说得对 我们分头去找
There has to be an exit somewhere.
应该可以找到出去的路
We'll help as well.
那么我们也一起帮忙找吧
We don't have any other choice.
没办法
Listen! Ran and Conan, you two should stay here.
听好！小兰和柯南留在这里
Miss Nana, it's best if you don't wander around.
奈奈小姐最好也留在这里别乱走
Fine...
好……
They are taking a long time.
大家真慢
Can't they find the exit?
难道找不到出口吗？
It'll be fine. They will find an exit
没事的 他们一定会找到出口的
and come back soon.
然后马上回来的
I guess I should go look for it too.
我也去找找看
My dad told you to stay here.
爸爸叫你留在这里
You're such a curious kid.
真是好奇心太重了
But...
但是……
It's a blackout.
停电
What happened? Why did the power went out?
什么事情 为什么电会
Fluorescent paint!
夜光剂！
Help!
救命啊
You shouldn't leave, Miss Nana!
不能离开 奈奈小姐
Could this blackout be...
莫非这个停电是……
Ah...
啊……
What?! What happened?
什么！发生什么事情了
What's wrong? Miss Nana just screamed.
什么事情 奈奈小姐的叫声
Inspector!
警部
Mouri, go to the power room!
毛利 快去电源室
Okay!
是
Miss Nana.
奈奈小姐
This is it.
就是这里
That's...
这是……
Move aside!
快让开
She's dead.
已经死了
The Seven of Spades and the Joker.
黑桃七和小丑
It's Murakami who did it. He's here
是村上 村上在这里
in this building.
在这个建筑物里面
Damn it, I'll look into it!
可恶 我要去调查一下
Mr. Mouri, it's too dangerous for you to go alone!
毛利先生 一个人太危险了
I'll go with you!
我跟你一起去
Mr. Shishido, please stop taking pictures.
宍户先生 请别拍了
Why? Now that we can't get any assistance from the outside
为什么 在支援完全不能到达
and a coroner is nowhere to be found,
检察官还没有检查之前
isn't it necessary to take photos of the crime scene?
有必要拍下现场照片
You are right.
你说得对
Please hand over the photos to the police after we go out.
那么出去之后请把照片交给警察局
Yeah, of course I will!
是 那是自然
But how did Murakami manage to kill her
但是村上在这么黑的屋子里面
when it's pitch-black here?
是怎么做到的
It's the fluorescent paint.
是夜光剂
Miss Nana's fingernails were glowing.
奈奈小姐的指甲在发光
What?! So that's what it is.
什么！ 原来如此
The nail polish which she received had fluorescent paint inside.
送给她的指甲油里面含有夜光剂
The middle fingernail.
含有夜光的指甲
Inspector, something looks strange
警部 奈奈小姐的左手手指
with the finger on her left hand.
有点奇怪
The nail polish came off.
指甲油掉了
Wait! Did her nail break off?
不！是指甲断了吗？
I think her fake nail came off.
我想应该是假指甲掉了
Fake nail?
假指甲
It's not her real nail.
不是自己真正的指甲
Some people would glue the designed fake nails
把一些设计过的假指甲
on their real fingernails.
利用黏着剂粘上去
That means the fake nail came off for some reason.
这么说是因为某种原因所以掉了
Found it.
找到了
But this seems irrelevant to this case.
好像和事件没什么关系
I suppose.
原来没关系
Someone had left a mark on her while grabbing her with their left hand.
是用左手抓的痕迹
It seems this person was grabbing her really hard.
看起来好像抓得很紧
That means the suspect is right-handed.
这么讲 犯人是习惯用右手的
I remember that Murakami is...
我记得村上是……
left-handed.
左撇子
The culprit is not Murakami!
犯人不是村上
Wait... at that time, the criminal
等等……犯人在那个候
Think, think!
想起来 快想起来啊
He used his right hand!
是用右手！
How can this be?
怎么会这样
I made a serious mistake!
原来我犯了一个很严重的错误
Inspector, I can't find Murakami anywhere.
警部 哪里都找不到村上
Maybe he had already ran away.
也许已经逃走了
That's impossible! There's no way out!
不可能的 因为没有出口
He has to be hiding somewhere.
一定是藏在某个地方
No, it's not Murakami who did it.
不 犯人不是村上
It has to be someone here.
一定是这里面的某个人
Who is it? Who killed Miss Nana?
是谁？是谁杀死奈奈小姐
That's right. At that time, the culprit
我想到了 那个时候犯人
kicked the juice can which I had put on the ground.
踢中了我放在地上的果汁罐
The juice spilled.
里面的果汁洒出来了
I remember there was at least half
我记得我摆在地上时
when I placed it on the ground.
还剩下半罐
If the culprit had kicked it,
如果真的是踢到的话
the juice would have stained
应该会沾到果汁 会留下痕迹
the culprit's trousers.
在犯人的裤子上
The one who killed Nana is among the four of them.
杀死奈奈的就是这四人之一
It's him! But why?
这个人！但是为什么？
I'm sorry, Mr. Sawaki.
非常抱歉 沢木先生
Mr. Asahi was killed because of me.
因为我使旭先生被杀
Now you can't manage that restaurant.
害你谈不成开店的事情
It's fine. I was planning to reject his offer.
没关系 因为我本来就是想拒绝的
I also plan to quit my job at the restaurant
我也想辞去现在的那间店
and go back to my hometown.
决定回到故乡去
I am the only child
因为我是独子
and I have to take care of my parents.
必须要照顾父母亲
Looking at the current situation, it's best we stay put.
现在最后别再乱动
Especially you, Mr. Shishido.
特别是宍户先生
I know. I'm the next target, right?
我知道了 下一个就是我了吧
I'll try not to get killed.
我会小心不被杀死
Inspector, I will not die here.
警部 我绝对不会死
No matter what happens, I'm leaving this place alive.
我一定要活着离开这里
Wait, perhaphs that guy...
等等 莫非那个人……
What are you doing?
你做什么
I figured everyone would be thirsty.
我想大家也许都口渴了
You fool! Don't run around on your own!
笨蛋 别擅自乱跑
We still don't know where Murakami is hiding!
因为不知道村上会躲在哪里
But there's no number in my name.
但是我的名字里没有数字
Here you go.
请
Here, Mr. Sawaki.
请 沢木先生
Thank you.
谢谢你
Kid, I'll have one!
小子 也给我一杯
Okay!
好
Japanese water tastes great.
日本的水真的很好喝
Yum!
好喝
It has to be him.
真的没错
But I don't have any proof.
但是没有证据
Come to think of it, where's that thing?
对了 那东西在哪里呢？
I've found it. The evidence.
我找到了 证据
What happened?
发生什么事情了？
I think that was an explosion.
好像是爆炸
Shiratori!
白鸟！
Mr. Shishido.
宍户先生
Protect Mr. Shishido!
快保护宍户先生
Yes!
是！
Mr. Shishido!
宍户先生
Mr. Shishido, where are you?
宍户先生你在哪里
I'm here.
我在这里
Put it out. Are you looking to die?
快灭了 你想找死啊
I am number two. So it'll be a while before my turn.
因为我是二 所以轮到我还有一阵
Mr. Sawaki, are you all right?
沢木先生 有没有事？
I'm fine... Will I be attacked again?
没事……请问我还会受到攻击吗？
Well...
那个……
Great! The emergency light is on!
太好了 是非常灯
That's...!
这是
Help, help!
救命啊 救命啊
I... I
我……我
Hold on to this!
快点抓住
Luckily we are alive.
幸好还活着
Ah! Where's Ran?
啊！小兰 在哪里
Did she...
莫非
Conan! Where are you going?
柯南！ 你要去哪里
Ran, where are you?
兰 在哪里
Ran.
兰
Ran, it's all right. Pull yourself together.
兰 没事的 振作一点
Shi... Shinichi.
新……新一
Conan.
柯南
It's useless.
没办法
That's right, I have the elastic suspenders.
对了 有伸缩背带
Shoot! My foot is stuck!
不好 脚被卡住了
No! No...
不行！不……
Ran...
兰……
Hey! Ran... Ran!
喂！兰……兰
Damn it!
可恶
I have to hurry!
要快一点了
Hey. Ran... Ran!
喂 兰……兰
Wake up!
振作一点
Dad... dad...
爸……爸……
You have to thank Conan for this.
你要谢谢柯南
Thank you, Conan.
谢谢你 柯南
It's all right...
不……
What happened?
怎么了
I ripped my stitches.
我的伤口好像裂开了
What?
你说什么
Look over there!
你们看那边
From Six of Spades to Two of Spades.
是黑桃6到黑桃2
Damn it! Is he planning to kill us all at once?
可恶 现在这里一次杀光吗？
You've gotta be kidding me!
别开玩笑了
But if things continue like this, it might really come true.
但是这样下去 也许真的会灵验
After all, we can't find a way out.
因为没有出口
There is an exit.
有出口
What?
什么
The glass windows were all broken.
那些被炸毁的玻璃窗
Right, we could swim against the current out to the sea.
对了 从那边逆游到海面就可以了
No, I can't...
不行的 我已经……
Don't give up so soon!
别讲那种放弃的话
I'll bring you with me!
我会带你上去的
Kid, I'll take you.
那么孩子 我来带你吧
I am fine on my own.
我可以自己一个人上去
I'll take you with me. Can you still take it?
我会带你上去的 你还能支持吗？
Inspector, I'll help you.
那么警部就由我来
Sorry.
对不起
I'll lead the way. Let's go.
那么就由我来带头 走吧
We're going. Now take a deep breath!
要走了 大大吸口气
Hold on tight and don't let go of my hand!
你要抓紧 别松手啊
Okay.
是
Grab my hand!
快抓住我的手
Please take care of Ran.
小兰就拜托你了
We're saved, right?
我们已经得救了吗
We are fine now.
已经没事了
Nishina! Nishina! Wake up!
仁科！仁科！振作一点
I'll give him CPR!
由我来替他做人工呼吸吧
I'm certified to give CPR.
因为我有急救执照
Wait! Officer Shiratori should give him CPR!
等等！人工呼吸就交给白鸟警员
Do it.
由你去做
Huh? I didn't say anything.
啊！我什么都没讲
Hurry! Shiratori.
快点！白鸟
Understood.
知道了
Mouri?
毛利？
Officer, the person who committed all these crimes
警部大人 这一次的一连串事件
is not Murakami.
犯人不是村上丈
What did you say?!
你说什么！
That's because the person who shot Hiroshi Agasa
因为射中阿笠博士的犯人
and killed Miss Nana
还有杀死奈奈小姐的犯人
is right-handed.
都是习惯右手的人
Right-handed?
右手
You are fine now.
你已经得救了
The suspect must have met Murakami some time ago.
犯人应该是在某个地方见过村上
So he knew that I shot Murakami in the shoulder ten years ago
十年前被我射中肩膀的事
and that he used to be a card dealer.
还有他本来是扑克牌的派牌师
The suspect used
听过他讲过的一些事
the stories he heard from Murakami.
而拿来利用
Used?
利用？
Yes, he noticed that the name of the people he wanted to murder
是的 他发觉到自己想杀死的人
and his name all had numbers.
和自己的名字里面都有数字存在
So he put the numbers and playing cards together
然后利用数字和扑克牌合并
in order to
把自己的罪行
frame everything he did on Murakami.
嫁祸成村上的罪行
So, he attacked Miss Eri, Hiroshi Agasa
那么攻击我和英理小姐
and me
还有阿笠博士 都是为了
so that we would assume that it was all Murakami's revenge plan?
让我们误以为是村上要报仇的陷阱
Exactly.
是的
But,
但是
who does he really want to kill then?
那么他真的想杀死的人是谁
Mr. Asahi, Miss Nana,
旭先生和奈奈小姐
and Mr. Tsuji.
还有辻先生 关于他这方面
Because after his eyedrops were replaced,
把眼药水掉包
it was very likely that he would have died.
从死亡的概率很大来看
So I guess he's also a target.
应该不会错
Mouri, so who's the culprit?
毛利 那么犯人到底是谁
The culprit is among us.
犯人就在这里面
What?!
什么！
I recall Miss. Nana embarrassed you in front of us.
我记得奈奈让你出丑过
It's not me! I didn't kill her!
不是我 我没有杀他
Yes! Because you were nearly killed too.
对！因为你差一点就被杀死了
The reason why the culprit blew up the restaurant
因为犯人炸毁海中餐厅
was so that you would drown since you couldn't swim.
想要把不会游泳的你给淹死
Officer Shiratori,
白鸟警官
when you gave CPR to Mr. Nishina,
你在替仁科先生做人工呼吸时
what was your first step?
第一步是做什么
The first step...
做什么……
Put his head in the right position and raised his chin
把头摆正 脖子提高
to keep his airway clear.
为了保证气管畅通
So, if you skipped that step
那么如果不作确保气管畅通
and pretend to give him mouth-to-mouth,
假装做人工呼吸
what would have happened?
后果会如何呢？
It'll get him killed, of course.
当然会死亡 那样做的话
Do you mean...
莫非
Yes, the person who killed Miss Nana and Mr. Asahi
是的 杀死奈奈小姐和旭先生
and almost killed Mr. Tsuji and Mr. Nishina
差点害死辻先生和仁科先生
is Kohei Sawaki!
的犯人 就是沢木公平先生！
That person is you!
就是你
Mr. Mouri, I was almost shot by the arrow too!
毛利先生 我也差一点被箭射中
You were the one that prepared the crossbow
那是你事先准备好的
after you killed Mr. Asahi
就在昨晚 这个乐乐广场里
here in Crystal Plaza last night.
把旭先生杀害之后
So the note on the ground?
那么掉在地上的纸条
And the secretary who called us?
还有打电话给我们的秘书也是吗？
It was all Mr. Sawaki's doing.
全部都是沢木做的
Of course, the nail polish which contained fluorescent paint
当然送给奈奈小姐
was also sent to Miss Nana by him.
含有夜光剂的指甲油也是他送的
What's his motive? What is it?
动机呢？动机是什么
I'm afraid it has something to do with his inability to taste.
恐怕和味觉伤害有关
Inability...to taste?
味觉……伤害
It means he lost the sense of taste for food and drinks?
就是不能尝出食物和饮料的味道
Yes, his sense of taste was injured.
是的 他的味觉受到伤害
This problem is mainly caused by stress
味觉伤害的原因是来自精神紧张
or external head injuries.
或者是头部的外伤
External head injuries?
头部外伤
So the person whom Miss Nana hit was...
那么奈奈小姐的车祸对象是……
Mr. Sawaki!
沢木先生！
Hold on a minute!
请等等
You say he had lost his sense of taste.
你说他有味觉障碍
But he was right about the wine which Miss Nana brought.
但是他猜中奈奈小姐带来的红酒
He got it right through the color and the aroma of the wine.
他是利用红酒的颜色和香味猜中的
How's that possible?
怎么可能
Mr. Sawaki told the name of the wine
沢木先生利用仅存的视觉和嗅觉
simply by relying on his sight and smell.
就这样把酒名给讲出来
However, as a sommelier who always asked for perfection,
但是对于要求自己做最完美的品酒师的
this was something that went against his ethics.
沢木先生来说这是违规的
That's why he was going to quit his job
所以沢木先生才会放弃做品酒师
and go back to his hometown.
决定回故乡去
But before that,
但在回去之前要对奈奈小姐
he wanted to take revenge on the people
还有让自己变成味觉障碍的人
who caused his inability to taste.
对他们复仇
You must hate them so much
应该是恨之入骨吧
that you broke the wine you saved up for your new restaurant.
恨到为了自己餐厅而准备的
The one you preserved well
一直珍藏着的
and cherished the most.
最宝贵的酒也可以打破的程度
That's why the floor in his apartment was damaged.
所以地上才会有那个洞
But how did you know that?
但是你是怎么知道的呢？
Because I saw him tasting seasoning.
因为我看到他在试味道
The thing he tasted was Chili Powder,
他所试的是 Chili Powder
which is very spicy.
就是辣椒的粉
A wine taster
因为从事品酒师工作的人
would never have anything so stimulating.
应该不会去吃刺激的东西
I confirmed my theory about his sense of taste
关于他的味觉受损
after I told Conan to bring everyone water.
由我叫柯南端出来的矿泉水已经证实了
Water...
矿泉水……
Only your glass of water
只有在柯南给你的杯子
had salt inside.
里面放了盐
But I didn't notice anything and drank it up.
可是我却没有发觉就喝掉了
You're right, I have lost my sense of taste.
我的确是有味觉障碍
But you can't prove that
但是无论如何都不能证明
I killed Miss Nana.
我杀死奈奈小姐
Of course I have proof.
当然有证据
It's in one of your pockets.
就在你的外套的其中一个口袋里
That's the cork on which Miss Nana drew on.
那是奈奈小姐开玩笑画的软木塞
Before she died,
奈奈小姐临死前
she still held it in her hand.
还拿在手中的软木塞
Why would that be in your pocket?
为什么会在你的口袋里
That's because when you stabbed Miss Nana from behind
那是因为你从背后刺杀奈奈小姐
the cork fell into your pocket
为了反抗
when she struggled.
软木塞就掉进口袋里面
That was probably when her fake nail
而掉在地上的假指甲
came off.
应该也是在那个时候掉的吧
How ironic for a sommelier to have the
身为品酒师的你
cork of a wine bottle be the proof of your crime.
红酒的软木塞竟然变成证据
There's also another proof
真是可悲 还有另一个
in your pocket.
我想应该还沉睡在你口袋里
The last playing card
和那些花样相同
of a similar suit to the others, the Ace of Spades!
用剩下来的黑桃A
Shinichi Kudo's card!
工藤新一的牌
The Ace of Spades?
黑桃A？
Mr. Mouri, you are totally right.
毛利先生 全部都说中了
Three months ago, after I got off work, I was almost hit by her car
在三个月前工作完毕回家的途中
on my way home.
和她的车相撞差点倒下去
Not long after that, I suddenly... couldn't taste anything.
过了没多久突然……感觉不出味道了
The doctor said that stress might be the cause.
医生说精神紧张也是病因
I felt hopeless and wanted to give up my career as a sommerlier.
绝望的我准备放弃做品酒师
Then I decided to find Nana Osanai who caused the accident,
决定找引发事故的小山内奈奈
Asahi, Tsuji who made me feel stressed
引起紧张的旭 辻
and Nishina to exact my revenge.
还有仁科 他们报仇
What did Mr. Asahi and the others do to you?
但是旭先生他们对你做了什么事？
Asahi noticed the popularity of wine
旭他发觉到有红酒热潮
and purchased all the great wines from abroad
利用他庞大的财产
using his money.
把国外的好酒全部买走
But he failed to preserve them well.
而且管理不好
Nishina, you used the title of a gourmet
仁科 你利用美食专家的名义
and wrote those absurd books!
胡乱写书
Teaching your readers incorrect knowledge about wines!
让读者对葡萄酒有错误的认识
As for Hiroki Tsuji,
还有辻弘树
he insulted my dignity as a sommelier.
他把我品酒师的荣誉给伤害了
Four months ago,
在四个月前
I attended a party which he held.
我出席一个他举行的派对
There he is!
来了 他来了
A badge like this would suffice, right?
徽章这样就行了吧
And here's your tastevin.
还有品酒器
Ah, how perfect.
啊 这个不错
You wanted to kill Mr. Tsuji over something so trivial?
就这点原因你就要杀害辻先生
Trivial?!
就这点原因？
You wouldn't understand
你不会了解
the feeling I had as a sommelier at that moment.
身为品酒师的我当时的心情
I became a sommelier because I dreamed of being an owner of a wine store.
我是为了成为店长而做品酒师的
But my dignity, personality, and knowledge
尊严 人格 知识
were all tramped on by his dirty feet!
全被那个男人的脏脚给踩烂了
You killed Murakami, didn't you?
你把村上丈给杀死了吧
Yes, on the day when Murakami was released,
对 村上出狱的那一天
I ran into him on the way to Mouri Detective Agency.
偶然的在毛利的侦探所前面遇上
It was the day when Uncle Mouri went out to play mahjong.
是老伯出去打麻将的那个中午
I figured Murakami would be useful,
我正想着要如何利用村上
so I used the fact that I'm Mr. Mouri's friend to invite him for a drink.
所以就以毛利先生的朋友身份邀请他喝酒
Murakami said that he hated Mr. Mouri at that time,
村上说虽然当时很恨毛利先生
but he wanted to apologize to Mr. Mouri now.
但是现在却想找他说抱歉
That's why he headed to the agency.
所以才来找他
It was right then
就在那个时候
that I came up with the plan of using playing cards to execute my plan.
想到利用扑克牌来进行计划
It was easy to kill Murakami
要把酒醉的村上杀死
who was already drunk.
是件很简单的事
Which means you had no grudge
那么你对毛利先生和警部
against Mr. Mouri and Inspector Megure, right?
一点仇恨都没有不是吗？
Exactly.
是的
Then why did you call Mr. Shishido and I?
把我和宍户先生叫到这里的理由
Just so you could make up the missing numbers?
只是为了凑数字吗？
Yes.
是的
Mr. Kudo, Mr. Mouri
工藤先生和毛利先生
and Officer Shiratori
还有白鸟警官
will definitely come over
只要我说被旭先生邀请的事
as long as I said I was invited by Mr. Asahi.
一定会跟来的
I actually thought, the Ace, Shinichi Kudo would come.
其实我以为A的工藤新一会来
It's such a shame that he didn't make it.
但是非常可惜 他没有到
Innocent people would die.
没关系的人也会死亡
Have you not considered that?
这种事情难道你没想过吗？
I blew up the restaurent
把海中餐厅炸毁
only to kill Nishina.
只是想杀死仁科
I don't care if someone else dies in the process.
其他的人是死是活和我无关
This place will collapse next.
接下来是这里崩塌
Since you can't find Murakmi,
找不到村上
this will eventually become a cold case.
应该变成个谜案
This place will collapse?
这里会崩塌
Mr. Sawaki, there's no escaping now.
沢木先生 你已经无路可逃了
You should surrender.
投降吧
Officer Shiratori, place Mr. Sawaki under arrest!
白鸟警官 快抓住沢木先生
What?
什么
What happened?
发生什么事情
Crap!
不好
Come here!
跟我走
She's taken away!
被抓走了
Why is Mr. Sawaki taking Ran hostage?
为什么沢木先生要抓住小兰
What are you talking about?
你在说些什么
You just exposed the crimes he committed.
是你讲出沢木先生的罪行
Me?
是我吗？
Don't move or I'll kill her!
大家都不准动 不然我就杀掉他
Damn it, how dare you use Ran when she's weak!
可恶 竟然利用小兰昏倒的时候
The explosion just now
因为刚才的爆炸
has caused the building to lose its balance.
使建筑物失去了平衡
Ran! Where are you?
兰！你在哪里
Over there!
在那里
Where is he heading?
他想到哪里去呢
He wants to escape using the helicopter!
用直升飞机逃走
What?
什么？
In order to escape from this place,
为了逃离这里
he pretended to be the secretary and booked a helicopter!
以秘书的名义叫来的
I won't let him do that!
我不会让他这样做的
Mouri, I can take it from here.
毛利 这里就交给我好了
Conan!
柯南
You guys, go find a place to hide!
你们快点去避难
But I can't swim!
我不会游泳
Don't worry, we'll find a piece of wood to stay afloat.
不用担心 去找块木板
Hold on to me tight, I'll help you get away.
紧紧的抱住 我会带你走的
Let's go, Shiratori!
我们走吧 白鸟
Yes!
是
Where is he?
在哪里
On the stairs!
在楼梯的上面
Using the elevator?
原来是利用电梯
Mouri, this way!
毛利 这边
Hurry, hurry!
快 快
Inspector Megure, how's Officer Shiratori's ability to shoot a gun?
目暮警官 白鸟警官的枪法呢
Same as mine. We are both pretty bad.
和我差不多 都不太行
What... what on earth have happened here?
这……这里到底发生什么事情
What are you doing? Bring the helicopter down!
你在做什么 快点着陆
Who is that guy? Why should I give him a ride?
那个男人是谁 为什么要载你
Damn it! Why can't this elevator go to the roof?
可恶 为何这个电梯不直达屋顶
Hurry up and bring the helicopter down!
快点降落
I'm the person who asked for the helicopter!
直升机是我请来的
Emergency! Emergency!
紧急联络 紧急联络
A man with a knife is holding a girl hostage
在乐乐停机坪有一持刀男子
on the helipad of Crystal Plaza.
挟持一名女孩
It looks like the building is crumbling!
这里已经开始倒塌
Please send back up.
请快派支援
Ran...
兰……
Stay away or I'll kill her!
不准过来 过来我就杀死她
Don't do this, Mr. Sawaki!
不要这样 沢木先生
Let go of Ms. Ran or I'll shoot!
快放开兰小姐 不然我开枪了
Interesting. I dare you to shoot at me!
真有趣 你敢的话开枪试试
His hands are shaking. At this rate, he'll hit Ran!
他的手在颤抖 这样会射到小兰
Shiratori, don't!
白鸟 快停手
Inspector, are you all right?
警部 你不要紧吧
It's useless to escape by helicopter.
利用直升机逃走也没用的
Let go of Ran!
快放开小兰
Shut up! I'll bring her along to kill Tsuji.
罗索 我要带这个孩子去杀辻
You want to kill Mr. Tsuji?
要杀辻先生
He couldn't attend the U.S. Open Golf tournament.
他已经不能出席全美公开赛了
Isn't that enough for you?
这样还不够了吗？
No, I'll kill him and then kill myself.
不行 我要杀了他之后自杀
This girl will die with me as well.
这个女孩也要一起
Mr. Sa... Sawaki.
沢……沢木先生
Shinichi... Help... Shinichi.
新一……救我……新一
If he takes Ran,
如果小兰就这样被他带走的话
she'll definitely be killed.
一定会被杀死的
This is bad!
不好 不要说是救小兰
Not only Ran, but everyone will be in danger!
大家都会有危险的
Give me the gun.
把枪给我
What?
什么
I'm gonna cut her throat!
我要割下去了
Shiratori, give me your gun.
白鸟 把枪给我
I said, give it to me.
我叫你给我
Are you kidding me? I won't give it to you.
别开玩笑了 我是不会给你的
What are you doing? Do it quickly!
你在做什么 快点
Okay.
我知道了
Kid, you bring it to me.
小孩 你拿过来
Do you want this lady to die?
难道你想让这女孩死去吗？
No, how can you let a child do such a dangerous thing?
不可以 怎么可以叫小孩子做这么危险的事
Hey~~
喂～～
Make it quick!
快点拿过来
No, Conan, you can't give it to him.
不行 柯南 不可以拿给他
No.
不可以
Good boy, now bring it to me.
乖孩子 快拿着它到这边来
Hurry!
快点
Hurry up!
快点拿过来
I see. That's what it is.
原来如此 原来是这么回事
That's why Uncle Mouri...
所以叔叔才会
Shi...
新……
Shinichi.
新一
Damn! Hey! Stand up! Hey!
可恶！喂！快站起来 喂!
That's so dangerous, Ran.
真是危险 小兰
I see. That's why Mr. Mouri fired that shot back then.
原来如此 所以毛利先生才会开枪
He didn't shoot to arrest the criminal
不是为了逮捕犯人而开枪
but to save the hostage.
而是为了救人质
That's right. A hostage with an injured leg
是的 因为脚受伤的人质
is a burden for the criminal.
对犯人来讲是个累赘
So dad was trying to save mom.
是为了要救妈妈
That's the real reason.
这就是真正的理由
Dad.
爸爸
Kohei Sawaki, you are under arrest
沢木公平 以杀人罪
for murder and kidnapping!
绑架罪的名义将你逮捕
Let go of me! Let me die!
快放手 让我死吧
I won't let you die.
我不会让你死的
You have to know how big a mistake you have made!
要让你知道犯下了多大的错误
That was so close.
真是千钧一发
Uncle Mouri, looks like your fear of riding helicopters
叔叔你的直升机恐惧症
is gone.
好像已经痊愈了
Ah... put me down!
啊……让我下去
Here.
给
I was shocked that the gun suddenly went off.
突然发炮 吓了我一跳
Gosh, luckily the bullet only grazed Ran's leg.
真是的 幸好是擦过兰小姐的脚
If the bullet went a few inches furthur then things would've been bad.
如果方向偏了 就完蛋了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Actually, my dad taught me how to shoot
其实在夏威夷的别墅里
and I've practised many times
爸爸教过我
when we were at our Hawaiian vacation home.
已经练过很多次了
How could I miss?
怎么可能射偏
But...
但是……
I gave Ran a bad memory.
给兰留下一个不好的回忆
Inspector, this is a good chance for you to recuperate.
警部 这是个好机会,请慢慢静养吧
That's exactly what I'll do.
我也正想这样做
Ah, don't take my hat off.
啊 帽子不用拿下来
Do you think Shinichi would have shot the same way you did, Dad?
新一也会像爸爸一样开枪吗
I don't know. If he's a good shot like me,
不知道 如果他有我枪法那么好
maybe he will.
应该会开枪吧
That's what I thought.
我也是这么想
Right, Shinichi?
对吧 新一
What's that?
那是什么
It's Shinichi's card, the Ace of the Spades.
新一的扑克牌 黑桃A
I've been holding it in my hand.
我一直紧握着它
Perhaps Shinichi was protected me secretly.
也许是新一在冥冥之中保护着我
Ran, the one who was saved by the Ace
小兰 被A给救的
should
应该是我
be me.
才对
You knew why Dad shot at you?
妈妈知道爸爸为何开枪的
Of course! We are a married couple after all.
当然 因为我们是夫妻
It's a husband's duty
丈夫保护妻子的生命安全
to protect his wife.
这是理所当然的
Then why did you leave?
那妈妈为什么要离家出走
That afternoon, that man
那个人在那天中午
said that the food I cooked tasted bad and didn't eat it.
说我煮的菜不好吃所以没吃
Huh?
啊
I endured the pain in my leg and cooked for him.
脚还在痛 却忍着痛去煮东西
But he was not grateful at all.
而他却一点都不感谢
Also, that man...
而且那个男人……
You fool! If you had time to cook all this
笨蛋 如果有时间煮这种东西
why not go rest and recuperate!
还不如快去休息
That's why we separated.
这就是分居的真正理由
Just thinking about it angers me!
一想起来我就生气
What an unromantic fool!
那个不识情趣的笨蛋
I see.
原来是这样
It'll be impossible for them to get back together.
这样要复合是很难咯
Come to think of it, Mom's cooking...
我记得妈妈煮的菜
really tasted bad.
好像非常的难吃